好了  灭了
Okay, it's done.
伙计们
Look, guys, for the future,
我不介意以后帮你们灭大蜘蛛
I don't mind killing the big spiders,
但那么小的不用我出手吧
But you have to at least try with the little ones.
佩妮  拜托
Penny, please.
我们面对的问题可比蜘蛛纲动物严峻得多
We're facing a far more serious problem than stray arachnids.
谢尔顿  没那么严重
Sheldon, it's not so bad.
不严重  简直是毛骨悚然
Not bad? it's horrible.
你觉得像听故事一样
I mean, you hear stories about this sort of thing,
以为不会发生在你身上
But you never think it'll happen to you.
他们不就是把你的饺子蒸了一下嘛
So they steamed your dumplings.
算了吧
Get over it.
拜托  换个新话题
New topic, please.
好吧  佩妮
All right, penny.
我借这个机会向你表达
Let me take this opportunity to point out
你今天看起来相当令人销魂
That you are looking particularly ravishing today.
霍华德  一千个套套都别想
Not with a thousand condoms, howard.
这么说还真有个数量
So, there is a number.
拜托  换个新话题
Okay, new topic, please.
你们知道楼上5A的人要搬出去吗
Hey, did you hear the people upstairs in 5a are moving out?
-别说  嘘  -虾米
- No, shh-shh-shh! - what?!
楼上的人要搬了
The people upstairs are moving out.
别说
No!
恐怖至极
The horror...
你干嘛非要提这事呢
Why would you just say something like that?
不  不  不
No, no, no, no, no, no, no...
那我还能怎么说
How else was I supposed to say it?
慢一点  就像放一条新买的鱼进鱼缸
Slowly. like putting a new fish in a tank.
不能直接丢进去
You don't just drop it in.
要连鱼带袋子先放进去一段时间
You let the bag sit in the water a while.
恐怖至极
The horror...
谢尔顿  我保证不会有事的
Sheldon, I'm sure it's going to be fine.
不可能会好了
No, it's not going to be fine.
改变总是不好的
Change is never fine.
人们说改变是好事  事实才不是
They say it is, but it's not.
亲爱的  你认识那些要搬的人吗
Okay, honey, did you even know the people that are moving out?
我从没见过他们
I never met them.
这样他们才完美
That's what made them perfect.
不用尴尬地在楼道打招呼
There were no awkward "hellos" in the halls.
不会有高跟鞋踩在木质地板的咔咔声
There's no clickety-clacking of high heel shoes on hardwood floors.
这一家就像是一窝小猫
They may as well have been a family of
从这个窗帘跳到那个窗帘
Cats just jumping around from drape to drape.
但没有尿液中恼人的氨味
Without that annoying ammonia urine smell.
我保证新来的也会安安静静的
Well, I'm sure the new people will be just as quiet.
你怎么知道
You can't know that.
你怎么可能知道
How can you possibly know that?
对  我不知道  告诉你
You're right, I can't. you know what?
任何人都可能租那个房
Anyone could rent that apartment now.
歌剧歌手啦 跺脚舞演员啦
an opera singer, the cast of stomp...
有条木腿的踢踏舞海盗啦
Yeah, a tap-dancing pirate with a wooden leg.
你干嘛要越搞越糟
Why are you making it worse?
我想搞好点  他不干而已
I tried making it better. he wouldn't go for it.
对啊  真是好主意
You're right! that's a great idea.
-什么  -我去租那个房
- What? - I'll take the apartment upstairs.
我就能摆脱我妈
I can finally get away from my mother
我们也有更多时间聚聚
And we can all spend some more time together.
明白我的用意吧
If you catch my drift.
恐怖至极
The horror...
《生活大爆炸》
第二季  第19集
等等 你真以为我会相信
Hold on. You honestly expect me to believe
社交礼仪规定
that social protocol dictates we
我们不惜弄伤腰骨帮沃罗威茨搬家
Break our backs helplping wolowitz move,
而他只要给我们买份匹萨吗
and then he only need buy us a pizza?
抱歉  事实就是这样
I'm sorry, that really is how it works.
你骗我
You' tricking me.
说实话  好处到底是什么
You tell me the truth, what do we get?
拉杰  搭救我吧
Raj, help me out here.
你能在PS3[索尼游戏机]和山地车中任选其一
You get to choose between a mountain bike or a ps3.
我就知道
I knew it!
PS3  肯定选PS3
Ps3, definitely ps3.
有谁会选山地车
Who would pick a mountain bike?
别再自责了  妈
Enough with the guilt, ma.
我们还会见面
We'll still see each other.
我每天晚上回来和你吃饭
I'll come over every night and have dinner with you.
你会才怪呢
The hell you will!
我这成什么了  星级餐馆吗
What am I running here, a fancy restaurant?
这里像橄榄园餐厅吗
Does this look like olive garden?!
我知道了  你生气
Okay, I get it, you're angry.
你不想让你的小小鸟离巢
You don't want to see your little bird leave the nest.
小小鸟
"little bird"?
你都快30了
You're almost 30!
看在上帝的份上  快飞吧
Fly, for god's sake!
行  我不走了
Fine, I'll stay!
高兴了吧  疯婆子
Ya happy, crazy lady?
肯定高兴死了
I sure as hell hope so,
因为你就是要毁掉我的生活
because you're ruining my life!
佩妮  我是莱纳德
Hey, penny? it's leonard.
好消息  你不用把头放进烤箱了
Good news, you can take your head out of the oven.
看来也不用戴这个了
I guess I won't be needing this.
苍天啊
Oh, no...
新来滴
The new ones.
他们来了
They're here.
冷静点  我们还不了解他们呢
Stay calm. we don't know anything about them yet.
你这是干嘛
What are you doing?
我查查有没有乐器
I'm checking for musical instruments.
像不像响板的声音
Does that sound like castanets to you?
盒子上写着厨房呢
The box says "kitchen."
那又怎样
So?
毒贩会在盒子上写可卡因么
do cocaine smugglers write "cocaine" on the box?
你们好
Hello?
-你好  -你好
Hello. hello.
-你好  -你好  -你好
Hello. hello. hello.
我叫艾丽西娅
I'm Alicia.
我搬来楼上住
I'm moving in upstairs.
那真是太好了
That is so great.
我叫莱纳德
Oh, I'm leonard.
我住下面
I live downstairs.
在这层的楼上  不过还是在你下面啦
Upstairs from here, but under you.
不是在你人下面  是你楼下
Not under you per se, but under your apartment.
挺好
That's nice.
是啊 挺好
Yeah, it is.
你的举动表明你有和她交配的冲动
If that concludes your faltering attempt to mate...
你好
Hello.
从一到十打分
On a scale of one to ten
你怎么给自己打分呢
How light of foot would you describe yourself
一表示一点也不像猫
With one being not cat-like at al
十表示你是猫中之猫
And ten being freakishly feline?
猫中之猫？
"freakishly feline"?
这是你给出的答案还是你没有理解问题
Is that your answer or do you not understand the question?
先不说这个
We'll come back to that one.
谢尔顿
Sheldon...
等一下
Hang on.
你目前抑或过去有没有跳过萨尔萨舞
Are you now or have you ever been a salsa
爱尔兰民族舞或者霹雳舞
Irish folk or break-dancer?
没
No.
你弄得别人不舒服了
You're making her uncomfortable.
抱歉
Oh, I'm sorry.
到现在为止你表现很不错
Well, if it helps you feel any better
希望能让你感觉好点
you're doing very well so far.
下个问题  你有生育能力吗
Next question，are you fertile?
什么
What?!
我在判定婴儿在我头上
I'm trying to determine whether crying
哭哭啼啼的可能性
Infants above my head are a possibility.
我现在没这个打算
I have no immediate plans.
改变主意的话  记得告诉我
If that changes, let me know.
最后一个问题  铺小地毯  赞成还是反对
And finally, area rugs, pro or con?
-赞成  -艾丽西娅
Pro? alicia?
-怎么  -欢迎你入住
Yes? welcome to the building.
莱纳德  太感谢你的帮忙了
Thanks so much for helping me, leonard.
感谢你给我帮忙的机会
Thank you so much for giving me the opportunity to help.
伙计们
Oh, hey, guys.
佩妮  这是艾丽西娅  我们的新邻居
Hey, penny. this is alicia, our new neighbor.
你好
Hi.
我在帮她忙呢
I'm helping.
看得出来哦
I can see.
艾丽西娅对音乐不感冒  无子女  赞成铺地毯
Alicia's non-musical, childless and pro-rug.
她还在我的考察期内  但我看好她
She's still on probation, of course, but I like her.
T恤很酷啊
Cool t-shirt.
是吗  我一般不这样穿的
Oh, yeah, I don't usually dress like this.
我去慢跑
I'm going jogging.
你好像从不慢跑吧
You don't jog.
现在开始
I can start.
行
True
但是对于你的穿着  更可信的解释是
But the more likely explanation for your
你又没干净衣服换了
Attire is that you're out of clean clothes again.
谢尔顿  我谢谢你
Thank you, sheldon.
佩妮  不客气
You're welcome, penny.
没事  你看起来很可爱
Please, you look cute.
瞧  我今天也穿得邋里邋遢的
I'm dressed like a slob today, too.
我觉得很惊艳啊
I think you look fantastic.
他挺会演戏吧
This one's a player, huh?
是啊  你要小心哦
Oh, yeah, be careful.
谢谢提醒
Thanks for the warning. okay.
-过会儿见  -拜拜
-I'll see you around. -see ya.
瞧  我今天也穿得邋里邋遢的
I'm dressed like a slob today, too.
鹦鹉学舌啊
Oh, mimicry.
我喜欢玩鹦鹉学舌
I enjoy mimicry.
我模仿过星战第六部的阿克巴上将
I've been working on admiral ackbar from return of the jedi.
"这是个圈套"
"it's a trap."
你得把我想象成一个大乌贼脑袋
You have to imagine me with a giant squid head.
"这是个圈套"
"it's a trap."
请进
Come.
祝贺一下  你终于洗衣服了
Congratulations, I see you did your laundry.
-这个  算是吧  -什么叫算是吧
-Well, sort of. -how does one "sort of..."
我买了新衣服  行了吧
I bought new clothes, okay?
莱纳德在不在
Is leonard around?
他在楼上跟艾丽西娅一起
He's upstairs at Alicia's.
好吧  行  没啥
Oh. all right, that's cool, no biggie.
他答应过帮我装打印机  再等一会吧
He said he'd help me set up my printer, but I guess I can wait.
他到底在楼上干什么呢
What exactly is he doing up there?
我认为是旨在毁灭我而进行的战略行动
In what I can only perceive as a tactical move to destroy me,
他跟库萨帕里和沃罗威茨在帮她装音响
He is with wolowitz and koothrappali setting up her stereo.
他们都在楼上 是吗
Oh, they're all up there, huh?
正常
Hmm, typical.
这很明显不正常
It's axiomatically atypical.
到现在为止  他们不了解艾丽西娅
Up until recently, they did not know alicia,
也没有在其他地方相处过
And had no encounters with her in a previous location.
以前他们从不上楼拜访房客
They never went upstairs to visit the former tenants,
而你将他们的行为鉴定为正常
So your characterization of their behavior as "typical"
是绝对的谬误
Is demonstrably fallacious.
好了  现在我看到一颗大乌贼脑袋了
Okay, now I see the giant squid head.
这下好  我又得重新来一遍
Oh, great! now, I have to start all over again.
我是想过租这房子
Yeah, I thought about renting this apartment,
不过我更像那种城里
But I'm really more of a
住跃层的黄金单身汉
"downtown loft" kind of guy.
不错啊  你现在住跃层吗
Cool. so are you in a loft now?
事实上
Oh, actually,
我现在阿塔迪纳那里和一个女人同居
I'm, uh, living with a woman in altadena.
不过是纯柏拉图式的  她同时是我的女佣
Purely platonic. she's also my maid.
听起来蛮不错的
Sounds like a sweet deal.
不过说实话  她差你太远了
I won't lie. it's pretty dope.
有人吗
Hello?
我过来给你带了些欢迎礼物
Hey, I just wanted to bring you a little housewarming gift.
那真是太好了
That is so sweet.
进来  我们打开看看吧
Come on in. let's open it. great.
你这裙子不错
Nice dress.
哪里哪里  我今天穿得邋里邋遢的
Oh, this? I'm dressed like a slob today.
他们正在帮我设功放
The guys have been helping me set up my sound system.
他们真是我有过最帅的技术帮手了
I've never had such good-looking technical support.
哪里哪里
Oh, pish-posh.
我怎么知道  它意思是不值一提
I don't know, it means shucks.
不值一提就是不值一提的意思
"shucks" means shucks.
你就不能等等再说这个
Let one go once in a while.
-对了佩妮  你知道还有什么奇事吗  -什么
-Hey, uh, penny, you want to hear something awesome?  -Yeah.
艾丽西娅跟你一样也是个演员
Alicia is an actress, just like you.
太棒了
That is so awesome.
想是这样想  但也没那么容易
Well, trying to be, but it's so hard.
是啊  跟我说说关于你的事
Yeah, I know, tell me about it.
我在这里待了足足三个月
I've been out here three months,
结果只搞到几个全国广告
And all I've gotten is a couple of national commercials
还有肥皂剧的小客串
And this recurring thing on a soap.
所以我现在还在蛋糕店工作
That's why I work at the cheesecake factory.
我感觉那些角色都不适合我
I'm holding out for the right part.
艾丽西娅  你DVD想怎么设啊
Alicia, what do you want as your default setting for dvds
5.1杜比还是家庭影院
5.1 dolby or dts?
你看着办好了  小可爱
Whatever you think is best, cutie.
家庭影院的低音更好  那就...
Well, dts has more low end, so...
好的
Okay.
对了各位  你们绝对会喜欢这个的
Uh, hey, guys, guys, you will really appreciate this.
我刚在网上读了个超赞的科学笑话
I read the best science joke on the internet.
艾丽西娅  你不懂的  但是他们很喜欢这个
Alicia, you won't get it, but it's right up their alley.
就是 从前有个物理学家
Anyway, so, this physicist goes into an ice cream parlor
每周都去冰淇淋店点两个圣代
every week and orders an ice
一个自己吃
Cream sundae for himself, and then offers one
一个放在旁边的空座位
To the empty stool sitting next to him.
好久都是这样 直到店主好奇问他为什么
This goes on for a while until the owner finally asks him what he's doing.
他说  因为我是物理学家
The man says, "well, I'm a physicist,
而量子物理理论 告诉我们总有几率
and quantum mechanics... Teaches us "that it is possible
这张空座位上面 的物质会变成一个
For the matter above this stool "to spontaneously turn into a beautiful woman
可能爱上我的MM
Who might accept my offer and fall in love with me."
店主然后说   这里每天
The owner then says, "well, lots of single,
都有大队单身MM
"beautiful women come in here ever day.
你干嘛不买冰淇淋泡她们
"why don't you buy an ice cream for one of them,
让她们爱上你
And they might fall in love with you?"
物理学家说  那个发生的几率又可能有多大呢
And the physicist says, "yeah, but what are the odds of that happening?"
这有点侮辱人  你不觉得吗
It's a little insulting, don't you think?
怎么会知道
How would I know?
我自己都不理解这有什么好笑的
I'm not even sure I get it.
对了  莱纳德
Hey, leonard?
你装好那个DVD以后
If you're done with the dvd player,
能不能再帮我装这个打印机
can you set up my printer?
乐意为您效劳
Uh, yeah, I'd love to.
等你装好她的
Uh, hey, maybe when you're done with her printer,
来装我的吧
You could set up mine.
你知道  你答应的...在一周前
You know, like you promised... a week ago.
好的  我会来的  先别烦我
Yeah, I'll get to it-- don't nag me.
好啊  美女
Hello there
是谁啊
Who is it?
你好  佩妮 门是开的  请进
Oh hello, penny. It's open-- come in.
这就叫讽刺
Sarcasm.
他们还都泡在楼上呢
Well, they're all still up there.
你以为我没听见吗
You think I can't hear them?
听听啊  呯呯呯
Listen to that. Stomp, stomp, stomp.
那是沃罗威茨踩他那个高跟皮鞋  没错的
That's wolowitz in his stacked heels that fool no one.
我不知道我为什么会介意呢
I don't even know why I care.
我才不介意
I don't care.
好吧  我介意得去背那个白痴笑话 但是我只介意到那个程度
All right, I cared enough to memorize that stupid joke, but that's all I care.
你知道吗  佩妮 蜂窝实际上
You know, penny, there's something that
很有趣的
Occurs in beehives you might find interesting.
有时候
Occasionally,
新的蜂王会在老蜂王还在位时闯进来
A new queen will arrive while the old queen is still in power.
此时
When this happens,
老蜂王要不另谋出路
The old queen must either locate to a new hive or
要不就去拼个你死我活
Engage in a battle to the death until only one queen remains.
你说什么呢  我被艾丽西娅威胁了?
What are you saying, that I'm threatened by alicia?
难道你说我是那个老蜂王 现在该滚蛋了
That I'm like the old queen of the hive and it's just time for me to go?
我只是在说蜜蜂
I'm just talking about bees.
探索频道在播这个
They're on the discovery channel.
你在说什么呢
What are you talking about?
蜜蜂
Bees.
我理解那个物理学家笑话了
I just got that physicist joke.
佩妮  谢谢你给我们买晚饭
Gee, penny, thanks for buying us dinner.
是啊  今天怎么了
Yeah, what's the occasion?
没什么  只是感觉应该
No, no occasion-- just felt like getting
给我的好朋友带点中国菜
some chinese chow for my peeps.
你记得我叫你点的鸡里面
Did you remember to ask for the chicken
莴苣要切块
With broccoli to be diced,
-不要切丝  -记得
Not shredded?  Yes.
-即使菜单明确说要切丝  -记得
Even though the menu description specifies shredded?  Yes.
-红烧饭  不要白烧?  -记得
Brown rice, not white? Yes.
-在韩国杂货店买质量好的热芥末
You stop at the korean grocery and get the good hot mustard?
记得
Yes.
在超市买低钠酱油?  -记得
did you pick up the low-sodium soy sauce from the market? yes.
不错
Good.
看看别人怎么做的  莱纳德
See how it's done, leonard?
我们今天晚上玩点啥
So, what do we got going on tonight, huh?
玩光晕  看太空堡垒  还是把曼妥思丢到可乐里?
Playing halo watching battlestar, drop some mentos in diet coke?
你想看太空堡垒?
You want to watch battlestar?
我还能说什么呢?  我不可救药地爱上了它
What can I say? I got my geek on, boys.
不  经前综合症的表现和这个不同
No, no, pms is different.
-谢天谢地你在家  我需要帮助  -怎么了
Oh, thank god you're home. I need help. what's wrong?
我接到电话让我去试镜
I just got a callback to audition
在里演一个被杀了的妓女
For csi to play a hooker who gets killed.
那我一定要看
Oh, I'd watch that.
但我的车还在修
But my car is in the shop,
我得在45分钟内赶到环球影城
And I have to be at universal in 45 minutes.
没问题  我带你去
Okay, well, I'll take you.
你真是及时雨
Oh, you're a lifesaver.
我可以在车上帮你对台词
I'll run lines with you in the car.
太好了
Great.
完事之后我带你们去吃中餐
And afterward, I'll take you all out for chinese.
实际上  不用担心  我们已经...
Oh, actually, that's okay. we already have...
嗯  饿死啦
Yum. starving.
在这儿吃中餐了
...chinese food right here.
他们已经走了  佩妮 听不到你说什么了
They're gone, penny. They can't hear you.
真不敢相信他们就这样任她利用
I cannot believe they're letting her just use them like that.
她一句话就让他们 像看家狗一样跟在后面
I mean, anything she wants, they go panting after her like trained dogs.
你知道就在上个星期
You know that just last week,
她让霍华德大老远开车带她
She had howard drive all the way to her
去橘子郡的叔叔家里取她的电视
Uncle's house in orange county to pick up her tv?
你曾让我和莱纳德帮你 从前男友那里要电视回来
You once had leonard and me get your television from your ex-boyfriend.
性质不同  谢尔顿
Apples and oranges here, sheldon.
这个女孩利用他们 靠脸蛋儿过着舒服日子
That girl is a user iceskating through the life on her looks,
占那些单纯的
Taking advantage of innocent,
意志力薄弱的男人便宜  去弱智电视剧试镜
Weak-willed men, getting auditions for stupid network shows.
现在还在我的地盘撒野
It just creams my corn.
-我能打断一下么?  -说吧!
May I interject something here? please.
你拿错芥末了
You got the wrong mustard.
你猜怎么着?  我拿到里那个角色了
Guess what? I got the part on csi.
哦  天哪
Oh, boy.
有什么不对劲么?
Something wrong?
不不不不  恭喜你
Uh, no. no, no, no, you know, congratulations.
我觉得你会是个出色的妓女的
I think you'll make a great hooker.
谢谢
Thank you.
我想问个问题
Hey, I got to ask you something.
物理学家挣多少钱啊
How much do physicists make?
不清楚 不会太多吧
Um, I don't know. I don't think a lot.
我想也是
Yeah, that's what I figured.
我闪人了
Well, got to run.
他们答应帮我装电视天线
The guys promised to set up my satellite dish
还有粉刷卧室
And paint my bedroom. yay!
我能说两句么
Um, hey, hey, can I talk to you about that for a second?
说什么
About what?
我想说  莱纳德  霍华德和拉杰
Well, you know, it's just that leonard and howard and raj,
他们不像一般的男生
They aren't like other guys.
他们很特别
They're special.
是很特别  那又怎样
Okay, they're special... and?
怎么说好呢
Oh, let's see. how can I explain this?
他们不会用保护层
Um, they don't know how to use their shields.
保护层?
Shields?
就像在星际迷航里
Yeah, you know, like in star trek,
作战的时候你会架设保护层
When you're in battle and you raise the shields?
老天这句话是怎么溜出来的
Where the hell'd that come from?
总之  你知道这样的男生很容易...
Anyways, um, you know how guys like this are, so...
请不要利用他们
Please don't take advantage of them.
谁说我利用他们了
Who says I'm taking advantage of them?
拜托  他们为你忙来忙去
Come on. they're doing everytng for you,
还不是你招惹他们
Because you're leading them on.
我让他们帮我的忙
So I let them do stuff for me.
他们高兴  我受益
They're happy. I get stuff.
有什么不好
Who cares?
和你所做的有什么不同
And how's it any different from what you do?
你说什么
Excuse me?
我看你也老围着他们
I've seen you around them.
好像你没做过同样的事
Are you pretending like you don't do the exact same thing?
姐姐  你过了啊
Okay, lady, you are way out of line.
到底谁过了?
Oh, I'm out of line?
对  你过了
Yeah, you're out of line.
你想怎么着
Well, what are you going to do about it...
婊子
Bitch?
我喜欢绿灯侠
I like green lantern.
我是说  他会被黄灯击倒
I'm just saying it's pretty lame that
真是太逊了
He can be defeated by the color yellow.
只有现代绿灯侠才怕黄灯
Only the modern green lantern is vulnerable to yellow.
黄金年代绿灯侠怕的是木头
Golden age green lantern was vulnerable to wood.
不错  我用一支2B铅笔就能把他们两个都解决了
Great, so I can take them both out with a number-two pencil?
天啊  女人打架!
Oh, my god! girl fight!
你干什么
What are you doing?!
我知道你肯定傻到想去劝架
I know you. you're stupid enough to break it up.
容我说一句  你今晚很清秀嘛
May I say you look very comely tonight?
谢谢
Thank you.
你说的没错  这匹小母马瘸了
You're right, this filly's been broken.
你帮她设置了家庭影院对吧
you set it on dts, didn't you?
没办法
I had to.
她叫人家小可爱嘛
She called me "cutie."
从艾丽西娅的个人主页看来
According to alicia's facebook page,
她搞上了一个CSI的制片
She's hooking up with one of the producers on csi.
电视上演死妓女  生活中是活妓女
Well, dead whore on tv, live one in real life.
很好
Oh, great.
她现在开始玩蹦床了
Now she's jumping up and down on the bed.